

## **ROMAN KOLISNYK**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

### **ABOUT ME**

I'm 24, and about 3 years I work as a web developer and just adore this profession.

I have experience working with heavy projects, and with the light ones. I use modern tools for web development, I often use frameworks, libraries. preprocessors, task managers, the console and "push" changes in Github. I know the principles of site building, BEM methodology, the principles of optimizing the speed of sites, the principles of semantic, clean and beautiful code, I like beautiful, fast and thoughtful interfaces, and I'm don't mind working on someone else's code. I'm not afraid of responsibility, I appreciate help, human kindness, I do my work seriously and always try to be better than "yesterday".

## **SKILLS**

#### Languages of communication:

Ukrainian (native), Russian (fluent), English (Upper-Intermediate level)

#### **Development languages:**

HTML, CSS, Javascript (ES5-ES8), PHP, Ajax Libraries / frameworks / preprocessors: jQuery, SASS, SCSS, Less, Bootstrap, Pug (Jade), Jekyll, VueJs+React (learning now) Instruments:

Gulp, Webpack, Git, console, npm, Bower Methodologies / layouts / other stuff:

FlexBox, CSS Grid, BEM, crossbrowser & adaptive layout, SVG, CSS & SVG animation, valid & semantic code, pixel-perfect

#### **Graphic apps / tools:**

Sketch, Photoshop, Avocode, Zeplin, Figma CMS:

Wordpress, Opencart, BlackLamp, GetSimple, Web-autoresource, Textolite Corporate tools:

Bitrix24, Redmine, Trello, Slack, Rocket.chat

### **EDUCATION**

# NATIONAL TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF UKRAINE "KIEV POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE" | 2011 - 2017

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Automation

- Department of automation of electromechanical systems and electric drive

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER, HEXA LLC

September 2018 - now

#### Duties

- · Creating sites from scratch
- Writing additional functionality/plugins
- Landing layout on CMS
- Creating emails & banners
- Debugging / fixing someone else's bugs
- Manual QA testing

#### Results

- · Launched 6 new unique projects
- Redesigned and rewrited 2 projects
- Fixed major bug with banners & created own plugin for its responsivity
- Created some plugins / modules for order forms

Stack: Javascript, jQuery, PHP, HTML, CSS, SASS, Ajax

#### WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER, FREELANCE

January 2018 - March 2019 (14 months)

#### Duties

- Creating of Internet shops, landing pages and turnkey sites
- Redesign of sites, optimization and bug fixes
- Writing additional functionality/modules, connecting plugins/ modules
- Creation of designs and landing layouts on CMS
- Working with hostings/servers/domains
- Working with SEO-specialists

## **INTERESTS**

- Technologies and programming
- Electroguitars and rock/metal music
- Table soccer
- Design and photo
- Interesting people
- Self-improvement
- Traveling
- Google, Apple, OnePlus

#### Results

- Launched 6 new projects (3 of which are online stores and 3 others are single-page sites)
- Made redesign and add-on functionality for the front-end online store Басейн.укр based on CMS BlackLamp on Yii2
- A new unique design for the BMWfix store has been created and layout has been landed on a new platform (Web-Autoresource CMS, written in PHP, jQuery and VueJS) to improve, automate and develop the project. Also some modules and extra-functionality were written/included for the front-end part of the site using PHP, JS and the jQuery library,
- Completely rewritten groomroom.net, redesigned, connected plug-ins, connected the admin panel and created and configured forms for recording clients

**Stack:** Javascript, jQuery, PHP, Yii2, HTML, Pug (Jade), CSS, SASS, Ajax

# WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER, SP-CARPARTS & PATRUBOK

January 2016 - August 2018 (1.8 year)

#### **Duties**

- Redesign of the site, landing layout on CMS
- Writing new functionality, fixing bugs
- Connecting modules
- Content Management
- · Code optimization and bug fixes
- Work with SEO-specialists
- Maintenance of the site, etc.

#### Results

- Redesigned site with responsiveness and cross-browser compatibility
- The module for notification of payment/return of goods was created, and partners program for downloading pricelists to the site by customers, module for downloading the price lists of suppliers, the online payment module LiqPay
- Implemented the ability to create news
- The site code was optimized and improved Google PageSpeed results from 35 to 92 points
- Google Analytics is connected and the site is displayed to the highest degree in the Google search results in collaboration with SEO specialists
- Connected and configured a lot of online catalogs and created their own product catalogs...

**Stack:** Javascript, jQuery, PHP, VueJS, HTML, CSS, SASS, Ajax